A Guide to the University of Virginia Inter-Fraternity Council Papers, 1958-2003
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Inter-Fraternity Council Papers, 1958-2003
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-23/4/18.081
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred from the Inter-Fraternity Council at the University of Virginia to Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, on February 21, 2008.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the records of the Inter-Fraternity Council at the University of Virginia, ca. 1958-2003, ca. 2,845 items, (14 Hollinger boxes, ca. 6 linear feet). The papers contain reports, case reports, correspondence, photographs, news clippings, manuals, fraternal organization agreements (FOA), by-laws, minutes, agendas, topical files, speeches, and talks.
Arrangement
These papers are arranged in five series: Series I: Inter-Fraternity Council News Clippings (Box 1); Series II: Inter-Fraternity Council Judiciary Committee (IFCJC) (Boxes 1-4); Series III: Fraternal Organization Agreement (FOA) and Rush (Boxes 5-7); Series IV: Governing Board and Presidents' Council (Box 8); and Series V: Inter-Fraternity Council Miscellaneous Files (Boxes 9-14).
Contents List
- Series I: Inter-Fraternity Council News Clippings
  - 1997 October-November Magazine-Link-Binge Drinking, (2 items) (Box-folder 1:1)
  - 1974-1983 February Newspaper Clippings, including The Cavalier Daily and the Daily Progress, (70 items) (Box-folder 1:2)
  - 1983 March-1985 February Newspaper Clippings, including The Cavalier Daily, (90 items) (Box-folder 1:3)
  - 1992 Sept-1993 May Newspaper Clippings, including The Cavalier Daily and The University Journal, (75 items) (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 1996 News Clipping, including national and local papers and memos, (18 items) (Box-folder 1:5)
  - 1997 January-1999 October Newspaper Clipping, including The Cavalier Daily, New York Times, The Washington Post, The Virginia Advocate, (90 items) (Box-folder 1:6)
- Series II: Inter-Fraternity Council Judiciary Committee (IFCJC)
  - 1979 October-December Inter-Fraternity Council Judiciary Committee (IFCJC)-Case Reports 79-9-79-12, (3 items) (Box-folder 1:7)
  - 1986 October-1987 February IFCJC-Case Reports-Hall v. Charlottesville Police, (4 items) (Box-folder 1:8)
  - 1988 March-November IFCJC-Case Reports-88-1-88-11, (11 items) (Box-folder 1:9)
  - 1988 September-November IFCJC-Case Reports-88-12-88-23, (11 items) (Box-folder 1:10)
  - 1989 January-1990 January IFCJC-Case Reports-89-1-89-8, (8 items) (Box-folder 1:11)
  - 1990 February-November IFCJC-Case Reports-F90-S90-3, (8 items) (Box-folder 1:12)
  - 1992 September-1993 February IFCJC-Case Reports-92-1-92-20, (20 items) (Box-folder 1:13)
  - 1993 March-April IFCJC-Case Reports-93-9, (4 items) (Box-folder 1:14)
  - 1994 January-November IFCJC-Case Reports-94-1-94-30, (30 items) (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 1994 September-1995 April IFCJC-Case Reports-94-31-94-50, (20 items) (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 1995 April-October IFCJC-Case Reports-95-1-95-21, (21 items) (Box-folder 2:3)
  - 1995 September-October IFCJC-Case Reports-95-22-95-42, (19 items) (Box-folder 2:4)
  - 1995 September-1996 March IFCJC-Case Reports-96-1-96-20, (20 items) (Box-folder 2:5)
  - 1996 March-September IFCJC-Case Reports-96-21-96-35, (15 items) (Box-folder 2:6)
  - 1996 September-November IFCJC-Case Reports-96-36-96-45, (10 items) (Box-folder 2:7)
  - 1996 December-1997 September IFCJC-Case Reports-97-1-97-20, (20 items) (Box-folder 2:8)
  - 1997 Sept-October IFCJC-Case Reports-97-1-97-43, (43 items) (Box-folder 2:9)
  - 1997 October-December IFCJC-Case Reports-97-44-97-67, (24 items) (Box-folder 2:10)
  - 1998 January-March IFCJC-Case Reports-98-1-98-24, (24 items) (Box-folder 3:1)
  - 1998 March-September IFCJC-Case Reports-98-25-98-49, (25 items) (Box-folder 3:2)
  - 1998 September-December IFCJC-Case Reports-98-50 - 98-70, (21 items) (Box-folder 3:3)
  - 1999 January-April IFCJC-Case Reports-99-1-99-7, (7 items) (Box-folder 3:4)
  - 1999 April IFCJC-Case Reports-99-8-99-33, (26 items) (Box-folder 3:5)
  - 1999 May-November IFCJC-Case Reports-99-34 - 99-50, (27 items) (Box-folder 3:6)
  - 2000 March-2001 February IFCJC-Case-Delta Upsilon Beta Bridge Incident, (11 items) (Box-folder 3:7)
  - 2000 March-November IFCJC-Case Reports-00-1 - 00-32, (32 items) (Box-folder 3:8)
  - 2000 November-2001 March IFCJC-Case Reports-01-1-01-11, (11 items) (Box-folder 3:9)
  - 2001 March-September IFCJC-Case Reports, items) (Box-folder 3:10)
  - 2001 August-December IFCJC-Case Reports-013-1-013-19, (19 items) (Box-folder 3:11)
  - 2002 January IFCJC-Case-Sorority Rush Snowball Fight Incident, (14 items) (Box-folder 3:12)
  - 1998 IFCJC-Policy Revisions and Elimination of Double Jeopardy, (7 items) (Box-folder 4:1)
  - 1997-1999 IFCJC-Reports to Dean Canevari, (2 items) (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 1985-1986 Papers of Mike Peoples, Vice President of Judiciary, (30 items) (Box-folder 4:3)
  - 1993-1997 IFCJC- Bi-monthly Updates, (6 items) (Box-folder 4:4)
  - [1997 December] IFCJC- By-laws and Standards, (7 items) (Box-folder 4:5)
  - 1979-1980 IFCJC- General Business, (14 items) (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 1981-1986 IFCJC-General Business, (59 items) (Box-folder 4:7)
  - 1997-2001 IFCJC-General Business, (13 items) (Box-folder 4:8)
  - 2001 September IFCJC-Judge Availability Schedule, (16 items) (Box-folder 4:9)
  - 1997 IFCJC-Memos, (18 items) (Box-folder 4:10)
  - 1996-2001 ICFJC-Sanctions, (29 items) (Box-folder 4:11)
  - 2001 IFCJC-Standards Board, (4 items) (Box-folder 4:12)
  - 2001 March 24 IFCJC-Theta Delta Chi- Complaint, (1 item) (Box-folder 4:13)
  - 1992 IFCJC-Trial By-laws, (2 items) (Box-folder 4:14)
  - 2001 March-April IFCJC-Weekly Reports to Dean of Students, (2 items) (Box-folder 4:15)
- Series III: Fraternal Organization Agreement (FOA) and Rush
  - 1991 May-2000 August Alpha Delta Phi, (12 items) (Box-folder 5:1)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Alpha Epsilon Pi, (10 items) (Box-folder 5:2)
  - 1992 March-2000 August Alpha Tau Omega, (5 items) (Box-folder 5:3)
  - 1991-2000 September Beta Theta Pi, (15 items) (Box-folder 5:4)
  - 1991-2000 September Chi Phi, (11 items) (Box-folder 5:5)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Chi Psi, (11 items) (Box-folder 5:6)
  - 1991-2000 August Delta Kappa Epsilon, (13 items) (Box-folder 5:7)
  - 1991-2000 September Delta Sigma Phi, (11 items) (Box-folder 5:8)
  - 1991-2000 September Delta Tau Delta, (13 items) (Box-folder 5:9)
  - 1991-2000 August Delta Upsilon, (16 items) (Box-folder 5:10)
  - 1991 May-1995 April FIJI, (12 items) (Box-folder 5:11)
  - 1999 Kappa Alpha, (2 item) (Box-folder 5:12)
  - 1991-2000 August Kappa Sigma, (12 items) (Box-folder 5:13)
  - 1991 May-2001 February Phi Delta Theta, (15 items) (Box-folder 5:14)
  - 1981 April-2000 August Phi Kappa Psi, (14 items) (Box-folder 5:15)
  - 1991-2000 August Phi Kappa Sigma, (11 items) (Box-folder 6:1)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Phi Sigma Kappa, (11 items) (Box-folder 6:2)
  - 1991-2000 August Pi Kappa Alpha, (13 items) (Box-folder 6:3)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Pi Kappa Phi, (13 items) (Box-folder 6:4)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Pi Lambda Phi, (15 items) (Box-folder 6:5)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Sigma Alpha Epsilon, (14 items) (Box-folder 6:6)
  - 1991-2000 August Sigma Alpha Mu, (15 items) (Box-folder 6:7)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Sigma Chi, (12 items) (Box-folder 6:8)
  - 1991-2000 August Sigma Nu, (12 items) (Box-folder 6:9)
  - 1991-2000 August Sigma Phi, (10 items) (Box-folder 6:10)
  - 1991-2001 May Sigma Phi Epsilon, (16 items) (Box-folder 6:11)
  - 1990 September-2000 August Sigma Pi, (14 items) (Box-folder 6:12)
  - 1991-2000 August St. Anthony Hall, (16 items) (Box-folder 6:13)
  - 1991-2000 August St. Elmo Hall, (9 items) (Box-folder 7:1)
  - 1986-1992 Tau Epsilon Phi, (8 items) (Box-folder 7:2)
  - 1991-1992 April Tau Kappa Epsilon, (9 items) (Box-folder 7:3)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Theta Chi, (12 items) (Box-folder 7:4)
  - 1991 June-2000 August Theta Delta Chi, (14 items) (Box-folder 7:5)
  - 1990-2000 August Zeta Beta Tau, (17 items) (Box-folder 7:6)
  - 1991 May-2000 August Zeta Psi, (12 items) (Box-folder 7:7)
  - [1995] Rush Orientation, (2 items) (Box-folder 7:8)
  - 1995-1999 Rush Orientation-Book, (17 items) (Box-folder 7:9)
  - 1998-2003 Rush Pamphlets, (6 items) (Box-folder 7:10)
  - 1995-1998 Rush Planning, (33 items) (Box-folder 7:11)
  - 1989-1999 Rush Proposals, (11 items) (Box-folder 7:12)
- Series IV: Governing Board and Presidents' Council
  - 1978 October-1982 December Governing Board-Agendas and Minutes, (18 items) (Box-folder 8:1)
  - 1983 January-1985 November Governing Board-Agendas and Minutes, (30 items) (Box-folder 8:2)
  - 1986 January-1992 February Governing Board-Agendas and Minutes, (56 items) (Box-folder 8:3)
  - 1980 February 18 Governing Board v. Sigma Nu-Case F79-17, (1 item) (Box-folder 8:4)
  - 1970 March-1982 December Presidents' Council-Agendas and Minutes, (62 items) (Box-folder 8:5)
  - 1983 January-1985 December Presidents' Council-Agendas and Minutes, (45 items) (Box-folder 8:6)
  - 1986 January-1991 February Presidents' Council-Agendas and Minutes, (40 items) (Box-folder 8:7)
  - 1991-1994 Presidents' Council-Agendas and Minutes, (50 items) (Box-folder 8:8)
  - 1995-1999 Presidents' Council-Agendas and Minutes, (102 items) (Box-folder 8:9)
  - 1978-[1989] Presidents' Council and Governing Board- Administration and Reference, (15 items) (Box-folder 8:10)
  - 1999 February-April Presidents' Council and Governing Board-Executive Board-Agendas, (3 items) (Box-folder 8:11)
  - 1998 March-1999 February Officer Transition Meeting, (2 items) (Box-folder 8:12)
- Series V: Inter-Fraternity Council Miscellaneous Files
  - 1989 September-November Activities Coordinating Committee, (2 items) (Box-folder 9:1)
  - 1986-[1988] Alcoholic Beverage Control, (9 items) (Box-folder 9:2)
  - 1998-1999 Alcohol Prevention Subcommittee, (9 items) (Box-folder 9:3)
  - 1984-1991 Alcohol Task Force-University and Statewide Initiatives, (54 items) (Box-folder 9:4)
  - 1992-1998 Alcohol Task Force-University and Statewide Initiatives (Box-folder 9:4a)
  - 1995 Alcohol, Tobacco, and Other Drugs Committee (ATOD), (6 items) (Box-folder 9:5)
  - 1999 All University Retreat, (8 items) (Box-folder 9:6)
  - 1998-1999 Annual State of the Houses Report, (1 item) (Box-folder 9:7)
  - 1999 February 4 Bid Day-Memo to Residence Staff, (1 item) (Box-folder 9:8)
  - 1997 Ot 17 Bid Day-Reported Incidents, (1 item) (Box-folder 9:9)
  - 1997 December Cab STAND Program, (1 item) (Box-folder 9:10)
  - 1998 Campus Fraternity Support Team Visit, (8 items) (Box-folder 9:11)
  - n.d. Charity Event Manual, (1 item) (Box-folder 9:12)
  - 1986 City Ordinances, pertaining to Fraternity Life, (1 item) (Box-folder 9:13)
  - 1996-1998 Correspondences of Alumni Council, regarding delaying Rush, (16 items) (Box-folder 9:14)
  - 1998 Correspondences of Dean of Students, regarding IFC, (16 items) (Box-folder 9:15)
  - 1991-1994 February Council on Community, (31 items) (Box-folder 9:16)
  - 1998-1999 Delta Phi (St. Elmo) Reinstatement, (2 items) (Box-folder 9:17)
  - 2001 February 15 Department of Education Grant -"Preventing High Risk Drinking Through Greek...", (1 item) (Box-folder 9:18)
  - 1991-1998 Facilities Management, (39 items) (Box-folder 10:1)
  - n.d. Faculty Fellows, (2 items) (Box-folder 10:2)
  - 1982-1991 Fraternity Alumni Council, (27 items) (Box-folder 10:3)
  - 1991-1998 Fraternity Alumni Council, (42 items) (Box-folder 10:4)
  - 1991 April 8 Fraternity Information Packet, (3 items) (Box-folder 10:5)
  - 1998 March 21 Fraternity Legal Aid Packet, (2 items) (Box-folder 10:6)
  - 1990-1993 Fraternity Report, (2 items) (Box-folder 10:7)
  - 1979-2000 Fraternity Working Group, (16 items) (Box-folder 10:8)
  - 1999 November 16 Go Greek Night Speech, (1 item) (Box-folder 10:9)
  - n.d. Government Major, (2 items) (Box-folder 10:10)
  - 1998 Grade Point Averages of University of Virginia Students, (10 items) (Box-folder 10:11)
  - 1988-1999 Greek Coordinating Committee, (38 items) (Box-folder 10:12)
  - 1989-1999 Greek Orientation and Leadership Seminar (GOALS), (19 items) (Box-folder 11:1)
  - 1974-1999 Greek Systems at other universities, including Washington and Lee, Colby College, Virginia Tech, University of North Carolina, University of Maryland, (17 items) (Box-folder 11:1a)
  - 1998-1999 Greek Week, (16 items) (Box-folder 11:2)
  - 1998-1999 Habitat for Humanity Philanthropy Project, (3 items) (Box-folder 11:2a)
  - 1995-1997 Health Behaviors Survey and Alcohol Mentoring, (11 items) (Box-folder 11:3)
  - 1991-1999 Historic Renovation Corporation (HRC), (18 items) (Box-folder 11:4)
  - 1958-1989 History of Fraternity/University Relations, (16 items) (Box-folder 11:5)
  - 1998 Holsinger Photograph Orders, (1 item) (Box-folder 11:6)
  - 1997 November-December Inter-Fraternity Pledge Council, (4 items) (Box-folder 11:7)
  - 1987-1991 Inter-Sorority Council (ISC)-Constitution, (5 items) (Box-folder 11:8)
  - 1998 Intramural Sports, (6 items) (Box-folder 11:9)
  - 1998 January 26 Jefferson Society, (1 item) (Box-folder 11:10)
  - 1997-2000 Leadership 2000, (36 items) (Box-folder 11:11)
  - 1998 October 18-24 Make-A-Difference Day, (1 item) (Box-folder 12:1)
  - 2000 February 1 Meeting-President Casteen and IFC Executives, (1 item) (Box-folder 12:2)
  - 1989-1990 National Chapter Advisors, (3 items) (Box-folder 12:3)
  - 1991-1992 National Fraternity Directory, (4 items) (Box-folder 12:4)
  - 1998-1999 March Newsletter-Fraternal Law, (3 items) (Box-folder 12:5)
  - 1999 Newsletter-Greek Forum, (2 items) (Box-folder 12:6)
  - 1995-1996 Newsletter-Inter-Fraternity Council Update, (3 items) (Box-folder 12:7)
  - 1999 February 4 One in Four, (1 item) (Box-folder 12:8)
  - 1991 March-August Operation Equinox, (33 items) (Box-folder 12:9)
  - 1988-1992 Order of Omega, (16 items) (Box-folder 12:10)
  - 1989, 1998 Orientation Materials, (8 items) (Box-folder 12:11)
  - 1999 Party Patrol, (5 items) (Box-folder 12:12)
  - 1999 Peabody Hall, regarding IFC office space, (4 items) (Box-folder 12:13)
  - 1999 September-October Phi Delta Theta-Case, (4 items) (Box-folder 12:14)
  - 1999 Phi Kappa Psi-Re-trial, (11 items) (Box-folder 12:15)
  - n.d. Phi Kappa Sigma Alumni Chapter Manual (Box-folder 12:15a)
  - ca. 1989 & n.d. Photographs of the Rotunda Esplanade, Tug-of-War, and presumably some of the Inter-Fraternity Council members, and Negatives, ( 1 oversize photograph) (Box-folder 12:16)
  - 1999 April Pi Beta Phi-Re-trial Request, (2 items) (Box-folder 12:16a)
  - 1994 Pledge Education Program, (10 items) (Box-folder 12:17)
  - 1995-1999 Police Complaints and Projects, (24 items) (Box-folder 12:18)
  - 1992 Positive Pledge Programs Committee, (6 items) (Box-folder 13:1)
  - 1998 March 23 President Casteen's State of the University Speech, (1 item) (Box-folder 13:2)
  - 1998 July President (IFC) Summer Mailings, regarding Alcohol Task Force, (11 items) (Box-folder 13:3)
  - 1998-1999 Presidents' (Fraternity) Update Letters to President Casteen, (25 items) (Box-folder 13:4)
  - 1998 Program Advisory Board, (8 items) (Box-folder 13:5)
  - 1982 November-1984 April Proposal to terminate Easters, Openings, and Mid-Winters, (20 items) (Box-folder 13:6)
  - 1990-1998 Rape Awareness/Prevention, (19 items) (Box-folder 13:7)
  - 1998 May Report-Nightline-"The Right to Party", (1 item) (Box-folder 13:8)
  - 1996 December 3 Report-University of Pennsylvania, (1 item) (Box-folder 13:9)
  - 1991-1992 Residence Life Packet, regarding Rush, (2 items) (Box-folder 13:10)
  - 1979-2001 Resolution, (10 items) (Box-folder 13:11)
  - 1999 June 4-6 Reunions Weekend, (3 items) (Box-folder 13:12)
  - [1991]-2000 Risk Management, (24 items) (Box-folder 13:13)
  - 1971-1978 Scholarship-Arthur P. Gray Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 13:14)
  - 1999 September Self-Governance at the University of Virginia, including Party Patrol and Judiciary, (5 items) (Box-folder 13:15)
  - n.d. Sigma Phi Epsilon-Apology, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:1)
  - 1991-1999 Southeastern Inter-fraternity Conference, (5 items) (Box-folder 14:2)
  - n.d. Speech-Al Park of University Interactions Governing Board, regarding Rush policy, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:3)
  - 1997 October Speech-Kari Fraser, regarding drunk driving, (2 items) (Box-folder 14:4)
  - 1994 February-October Spirit of UVA Days Proposal, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:5)
  - [1988] Standards and Procedures of Fraternities, (3 items) (Box-folder 14:6)
  - 1982-1992 State of the Fraternity System, (28 items) (Box-folder 14:7)
  - 1999 Status Recognition of New Fraternities, (3 items) (Box-folder 14:8)
  - 1986 November Student Activities Survey, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:9)
  - n.d. Student Assistant Mentor (SAM) Program and related news clippings, (3 items) (Box-folder 14:10)
  - 1996-1997 Substance-Free Housing Task Force, (2 items) (Box-folder 14:11)
  - 1982 Theta Chi Alumni Manual (Box-folder 14:11a)
  - 1986-1992 Venable Neighborhood Association, (25 items) (Box-folder 14:12)
  - 1979 Virginia Collegiate Services, (1 item) (Box-folder 14:13)
  - 1995 Wellness Week, (5 items) (Box-folder 14:14)
  - 1996 Wesley Foundation Center, (2 items) (Box-folder 14:15)
  - n.d. White Pine State University Simulation Exercise (Box-folder 14:16)